<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>The great question, of the authority of the arch-bishops, bishops, &amp; clergy of the present constitution of the Church of England estalished by law, whether truly apostolical, or only political, regal, and parliamentary? Faithfully examined, and clearly resolved.</title>
         </titleStmt>
         <editionStmt>
            <edition>
               <date>1690</date>
            </edition>
         </editionStmt>
         <extent>Approx. 36 KB of XML-encoded text transcribed from 8 1-bit group-IV TIFF page images.</extent>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>Text Creation Partnership,</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Ann Arbor, MI ; Oxford (UK) :</pubPlace>
            <date when="2011-12">2011-12 (EEBO-TCP Phase 2).</date>
            <idno type="DLPS">A41939</idno>
            <idno type="STC">Wing G1745A</idno>
            <idno type="STC">ESTC R223655</idno>
            <idno type="EEBO-CITATION">99833944</idno>
            <idno type="PROQUEST">99833944</idno>
            <idno type="VID">38423</idno>
            <availability>
               <p>To the extent possible under law, the Text Creation Partnership has waived all copyright and related or neighboring rights to this keyboarded and encoded edition of the work described above, according to the terms of the CC0 1.0 Public Domain Dedication (http://creativecommons.org/publicdomain/zero/1.0/). This waiver does not extend to any page images or other supplementary files associated with this work, which may be protected by copyright or other license restrictions. Please go to https://www.textcreationpartnership.org/ for more information about the project.</p>
            </availability>
         </publicationStmt>
         <seriesStmt>
            <title>Early English books online.</title>
         </seriesStmt>
         <notesStmt>
            <note>(EEBO-TCP ; phase 2, no. A41939)</note>
            <note>Transcribed from: (Early English Books Online ; image set 38423)</note>
            <note>Images scanned from microfilm: (Early English books, 1641-1700 ; 1833:7)</note>
         </notesStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <biblFull>
               <titleStmt>
                  <title>The great question, of the authority of the arch-bishops, bishops, &amp; clergy of the present constitution of the Church of England estalished by law, whether truly apostolical, or only political, regal, and parliamentary? Faithfully examined, and clearly resolved.</title>
               </titleStmt>
               <extent>12 p.   </extent>
               <publicationStmt>
                  <publisher>s.n.,</publisher>
                  <pubPlace>[London? :</pubPlace>
                  <date>1690]</date>
               </publicationStmt>
               <notesStmt>
                  <note>Caption title.</note>
                  <note>Imprint from Wing.</note>
                  <note>Reproduction of the original in the British Library.</note>
               </notesStmt>
            </biblFull>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <projectDesc>
            <p>Created by converting TCP files to TEI P5 using tcp2tei.xsl,
      TEI @ Oxford.
      </p>
         </projectDesc>
         <editorialDecl>
            <p>EEBO-TCP is a partnership between the Universities of Michigan and Oxford and the publisher ProQuest to create accurately transcribed and encoded texts based on the image sets published by ProQuest via their Early English Books Online (EEBO) database (http://eebo.chadwyck.com). The general aim of EEBO-TCP is to encode one copy (usually the first edition) of every monographic English-language title published between 1473 and 1700 available in EEBO.</p>
            <p>EEBO-TCP aimed to produce large quantities of textual data within the usual project restraints of time and funding, and therefore chose to create diplomatic transcriptions (as opposed to critical editions) with light-touch, mainly structural encoding based on the Text Encoding Initiative (http://www.tei-c.org).</p>
            <p>The EEBO-TCP project was divided into two phases. The 25,368 texts created during Phase 1 of the project (2000-2009), initially available only to institutions that contributed to their creation, were released into the public domain on 1 January 2015. The approximately 40,000 texts produced during Phase 2 (2009- ), of which 34,963 had been released as of 2020, originally similarly restricted, were similarly freed from all restrictions on 1 August 2020. As of that date anyone is free to take and use these texts for any purpose (modify them, annotate them, distribute them, etc.). But we do respectfully request that due credit and attribution be given to their original source.</p>
            <p>Users should be aware of the process of creating the TCP texts, and therefore of any assumptions that can be made about the data.</p>
            <p>Text selection was based on the New Cambridge Bibliography of English Literature (NCBEL). If an author (or for an anonymous work, the title) appears in NCBEL, then their works are eligible for inclusion. Selection was intended to range over a wide variety of subject areas, to reflect the true nature of the print record of the period. In general, first editions of a works in English were prioritized, although there are a number of works in other languages, notably Latin and Welsh, included and sometimes a second or later edition of a work was chosen if there was a compelling reason to do so.</p>
            <p>Image sets were sent to external keying companies for transcription and basic encoding. Quality assurance was then carried out by editorial teams in Oxford and Michigan. 5% (or 5 pages, whichever is the greater) of each text was proofread for accuracy and those which did not meet QA standards were returned to the keyers to be redone. After proofreading, the encoding was enhanced and/or corrected and characters marked as illegible were corrected where possible up to a limit of 100 instances per text. Any remaining illegibles were encoded as &lt;gap&gt;s. Understanding these processes should make clear that, while the overall quality of TCP data is very good, some errors will remain and some readable characters will be marked as illegible. Users should bear in mind that in all likelihood such instances will never have been looked at by a TCP editor.</p>
            <p>The texts were encoded and linked to page images in accordance with level 4 of the TEI in Libraries guidelines.</p>
            <p>Copies of the texts have been issued variously as SGML (TCP schema; ASCII text with mnemonic sdata character entities); displayable XML (TCP schema; characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or text strings within braces); or lossless XML (TEI P5, characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or TEI g elements).</p>
            <p>Keying and markup guidelines are available at the <ref target="http://www.textcreationpartnership.org/docs/.">Text Creation Partnership web site</ref>.</p>
         </editorialDecl>
         <listPrefixDef>
            <prefixDef ident="tcp"
                       matchPattern="([0-9\-]+):([0-9IVX]+)"
                       replacementPattern="http://eebo.chadwyck.com/downloadtiff?vid=$1&amp;page=$2"/>
            <prefixDef ident="char"
                       matchPattern="(.+)"
                       replacementPattern="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/textcreationpartnership/Texts/master/tcpchars.xml#$1"/>
         </listPrefixDef>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="eng">eng</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="http://authorities.loc.gov/">
               <term>Church of England --  Government --  Early works to 1800.</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2010-02</date>
            <label>TCP</label>Assigned for keying and markup</change>
         <change>
            <date>2010-02</date>
            <label>SPi Global</label>Keyed and coded from ProQuest page images</change>
         <change>
            <date>2010-04</date>
            <label>Megan Marion</label>Sampled and proofread</change>
         <change>
            <date>2010-04</date>
            <label>Megan Marion</label>Text and markup reviewed and edited</change>
         <change>
            <date>2011-06</date>
            <label>pfs</label>Batch review (QC) and XML conversion</change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text xml:lang="eng">
      <body>
         <div type="text">
            <pb facs="tcp:38423:1" rendition="simple:additions"/>
            <head>The Great Queſtion, Of the AUTHORITY of the Arch-Biſhops, Biſhops, &amp; Clergy, Of the preſent Conſtitution of the <hi>Church of England</hi> Eſtabliſhed by LAW, Whether truly <hi>Apoſtolical,</hi> or only <hi>Political,</hi> Regal, and Parliamentary? Faithfully Examined, and clearly Reſolved.</head>
            <p>TO pretend <hi>Authority,</hi> and act without any, is doubly in<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>jurious; both to thoſe, whoſe Authority is pretended, and to all who are concerned in the Exerciſe of it. This is univerſally true; but may be much <hi>aggravated</hi> by the Circumſtances of the Perſons any way concerned, and of the Matters wherein it is pretended and exerciſed. And from hence it may be perceived, that Pretence of <hi>Epiſcopal Authority</hi> is of it ſelf a Crime of a very high degree; and yet this may be <hi>farther ag<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>gravated</hi> by the Addition of another Crime of like nature and de<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>gree; that is, <hi>Schiſm;</hi> when the Authority is not only pretended and uſurped, but with this farther Iniquity, to caſt out, or keep out, a true and juſt Authority. And from hence may be perceived, how reaſonable it is that no Authority be admitted, truſted, or ſubmitted to, without good Evidence, or ſufficient grounds: And therefore ſo long as it is <hi>doubtful,</hi> it is as none till the Doubt be cleared, or it be ratified and confirmed by juſt and competent Authority. And becauſe the Epiſcopal Authority of the whole Succeſſion of thoſe, who are now in Poſſeſſion of the Temporalities of the Biſhops of <hi>England</hi> from <hi>Cranmer,</hi> hath been queſtioned and denied from the beginning, it is the Concern of every Perſon in this Nation to be well ſatisfied of the Authority they pretend, or elſe to ſeek for ſome other, that is without queſtion. And this is yet the more neceſſary or reaſonable, becauſe there are no Churches, either in the <hi>East,</hi> or in the <hi>West,</hi> or any part of the World, whoſe Epiſcopal or Eccleſiaſtical Authority is denied or queſtioned
<pb facs="tcp:38423:2"/>
               <pb facs="tcp:38423:2" rendition="simple:additions"/>
               <gap reason="duplicate" extent="1 page">
                  <desc>〈1 page duplicate〉</desc>
               </gap>
               <pb n="2" facs="tcp:38423:3"/>at this day, but thoſe, which call themſelves <hi>Reformed</hi> Churches, and yet have no Communion with any Catholick Church in being before the pretended Reformation.</p>
            <p>Tho' <hi>Cranmer</hi> had no true Canonical Election, nor was qua<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lified for Epiſcopal Conſecration, having married a ſecond Wife, and ſhe living, tho' kept conceiled, yet ſince his Conſecration hath not been queſtioned, and there are greater Matters to be conſi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dered, I ſhall paſs by that, and ſuppoſing the Ordination and Con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſecration which he received to be good, proceed immediately to the Conſideration of the Ordination and Conſecration of others by Him; Whether that might confer any true Apoſtolical, either Epiſcopal, or Sacerdotal, Authority? and admitting it might till <hi>October</hi> 1535. when he received a <hi>Commiſſion</hi> exactly agreeing with that publiſhed in the <hi>Hiſtory of the Reformation, Vol.</hi> 1. <hi>Rec.</hi> 14. <hi>p.</hi> 184. and in all but one particular with his ſecond Commiſſion in <hi>Vol.</hi> 2. <hi>Rec.</hi> 2. <hi>p.</hi> 90. as appears by a Note of Dr. <hi>Yale,</hi> principal Regiſtrary and Vicar-General to <hi>Mat. Parker,</hi> upon a Tranſcript, (probably for a Precedent of ſuch Commiſſions) wherein are noted the Dates of divers others then, and ſoon after, to the Arch-Biſhop of <hi>York, &amp;c.</hi> Yet is there great reaſon to doubt of it afterward. This is a Matter of great moment, which had been buried in Si<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lence and Oblivion for ſome time, but, undoubtedly by a ſpecial order of Providence. brought to Light by two late Writers, who did good Service to neceſſary Truth, what-ever either of them in<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tended. For, 1ſt, from hence may be obſerved divers matters of Fact of great Conſequence.</p>
            <p n="1">1. <hi>That it was</hi> Cranmer<hi>'s</hi> Project and Invention; <hi>which is con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>firmed by its agreement with his Principles otherwiſe declared; but is diſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ingenuouſly, diſhoneſtly and falſly imputed to</hi> Bonner, <hi>by the Hiſtorian, (and ſuch as contrary to their own knowledge have written after him) for ſetting a wicked Example.</hi> 2. <hi>That it was not he alone, but the Arch-Biſhop of</hi> York, <hi>and the Biſhops of</hi> London, Lincoln, Wincheſter, &amp;c. <hi>who accepted ſuch Commiſſions; undoubtedly</hi> all of both Provinces <hi>either then, or ſoon after: For if any one had dared to ſtand out, it would have been ſoon publickly known, and taken notice of: Tho' he and his Friend</hi> Cromwell <hi>betrayed them all into it.</hi> 3. <hi>That this was</hi> continued in that Reign, <hi>may well be concluded from the Temper of that King, who would abate nothing of what he had once gotten, the Spirit, and Concern of</hi> Cranmer, <hi>Arch-Biſhop, and the Record of</hi> Bonner<hi>'s Commiſſion</hi> 4 <hi>years after, and the Order of Council in the beginning of K.</hi> Edward<hi>'s Reign, to take out Commiſſions of the ſame form.</hi> 4. <hi>That</hi> all Pro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>motions afterward <hi>in his</hi> (Cranmer<hi>'s</hi>) <hi>time to any Epiſcopal Sees was</hi>
               <pb n="3" facs="tcp:38423:3"/>by Commiſſions: <hi>Which is confirmed by the Order of Council aforeſaid, and the</hi> Stat. 1. Ed. 6. c. 2. <hi>Paſſim obtinuit ab Anno</hi> 1535. <hi>ad Annum</hi> 1553. ſays <hi>Wharton de Epiſc. Lond. in Bonner.</hi>
            </p>
            <p n="2">And, <hi>2dly,</hi> from this matter of Fact it may be farther obſerved, that the Authority of theſe Perſons, whom we <hi>preſumed</hi> to be true <hi>Biſhops of the Church of England,</hi> without all doubt, is not what we preſumed, unqueſtionable, but at leaſt greatly doubtful, not only in reſpect of Title to their Sees, but in reſpect of their Epiſcopal Authority it ſelf, <hi>Whether they have any true Apoſtolical, or Eccle<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtiaſtical, Authority at all, or ſo much as Sacerdotal, or Clerical, or any other than meerly Political?</hi> And if this be ſo, it<note n="*" place="margin">
                  <hi>V.</hi> Dodwell of Schiſm, <hi>c.</hi> 18.</note> concerns all to look about us, to ſecure our Right and Title, not to any preſent Temporal Eſtates upon Earth, but to our future Eternal State in Heaven; and more eſpecially after ſufficient Notice. The <hi>Doubts</hi> are divers, and moſt of them <hi>Fatal,</hi> if but any one of thoſe prove clear and undeniable againſt it. I ſhall propoſe only theſe following:
<list>
                  <item>1. <hi>Whether the</hi> Commiſſion <hi>doth not contain matter Heretical and Schiſmatical?</hi>
                  </item>
                  <item>2. <hi>Whether the</hi> Acceptance <hi>of an Heretical and Schiſmatical Com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>miſſion doth not make the Acceptors guilty of both, and by Conſequence vitiate, or make the Ordination and Conſecration of ſuch Perſons by ſuch Perſons irregular?</hi>
                  </item>
                  <item>3. <hi>Whether a</hi> Commiſſion <hi>declaring All Authority and Juriſdiction, as well Eccleſiaſtical as Secular, to proceed originally from the Regal Power, as the Supream Head and Spring; and that they, who before exerciſed any ſuch, did it only</hi> Precario, &amp;c. <hi>and delegating by the Words,</hi> Tibi Vices noſtras committimus, <hi>Licence to Ordain,</hi> &amp;c. Vice, Nomine, &amp; Authoritate noſtris; — per praeſentes ad noſtri Bene<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>placiti voluntatem duraturas, <hi>doth convey any other Authority than what is really exiſtent in the Fountain, at the time of the Grant? that is, meerly Political, unleſs the King had received alſo by ſpecial Conſecration any truly Epiſcopal.</hi>
                  </item>
                  <item>4. <hi>Whether the</hi> Acceptance <hi>of ſuch a Commiſſion be not a</hi> Recog<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nition <hi>of ſuch an Authority as is therein declared, and a Renunciation of the Apoſtolical received from the Church?</hi>
                  </item>
                  <item>5. <hi>Whether a Perſon</hi> acting under ſuch a Commiſſion <hi>may be in<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tended to confer any other Authority than what is conveyed to him by ſuch Commiſſion?</hi>
                  </item>
                  <item>6. <hi>Whether, when both the Conſecrators and Conſecrated have before accepted ſuch Commiſſions, the</hi> Conſecration <hi>is to be intended to be other than a</hi> Solemnity of Inveſtiture <hi>(like the Coronation) to the Office deligated by the Commiſſion, according to</hi> Cranmer's <hi>Opinion?</hi>
                  </item>
               </list>
            </p>
            <pb n="4" facs="tcp:38423:4"/>
            <p>All theſe <hi>Doubts</hi> ariſe from the Matters of Fact aforeſaid, and do all occur and concur in the Caſe of every Biſhop, who was made ſince the Project of Commiſſions was brought into uſe during the Reigns of <hi>Hen.</hi> 8. and <hi>Edw.</hi> 6. and all but the laſt in the Caſe of all, who were Biſhops at that time, and accepted any ſuch Com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>miſſion: but all, and ſomething more peculiar in the Caſe of the Conſecrators of <hi>Matt. Parker,</hi> the firſt Arch-Biſhop ſince the ſe<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cond Schiſm, in the firſt Year of Qu. <hi>Elizabeth,</hi> and the reſt then promoted, concerning their Conſecration.</p>
            <p>The Queen had ordered a <hi>Commiſſion</hi> to <hi>Cuthbert,</hi> Biſhop of <hi>Durham; Gilbert,</hi> of <hi>Bath; David,</hi> of <hi>Peterborough; Anthony,</hi> of <hi>Landaff; William Barlow,</hi> Biſhop; and <hi>John Scory,</hi> Biſhop, dated <hi>Sept.</hi> 9. <hi>to conſecrate Matt. Parker,</hi> who was elected <hi>Aug.</hi> 1. by the Dean of <hi>Canterbury,</hi> and four Prebendaries, the reſt not appearing, (<hi>Wharton p.</hi> 153.) and when nothing was done by them in near three months time, ſhe granted another, dated <hi>Dec.</hi> 6. to <hi>Landaff, Barlow,</hi> and <hi>Scory,</hi> aforeſaid; and to <hi>Coverdale,</hi> ſome time of <hi>Ex<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>eter; <hi>Richard,</hi>
               </hi> Suffragan of <hi>Bedford; John,</hi> Suffragan of <hi>Thet<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ford;</hi> and <hi>John Bale,</hi> Biſhop of <hi>Oſſory</hi> in <hi>Ireland,</hi> for them, or any four of them, to confirm and conſecrate him. Both are recited by <hi>Bramhall, p.</hi> 449, 450. and the laſt was executed by <hi>Barlow, Scory, Coverdale,</hi> and <hi>Iohn,</hi> Biſhop of <hi>Bedford,</hi> as it is in the Re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>giſter <hi>apud Bramhall, p.</hi> 1043.</p>
            <p>
               <hi>Barlow</hi> was the Man, to whom <hi>(apud Menſam Cathedrâ ſe<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dente) Parker</hi> was preſented by the reſt to be conſecrated Arch-Biſhop, and who performed the Office, as is related in the Regiſter. But it is a wonderful thing, by what Chance or Providence it hap<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pened, that his own Conſecration, who was the principal Actor in this, ſhould no where appear, nor any poſitive Proof of it be found, in more than Fourſcore Years, ſince it was firſt queſtioned, by all the Search that could be made by ſo many learned, curious and in<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>duſtrious Perſons as Mr. <hi>Maſon</hi> imployed by the Arch-Biſhop, and all the Aſſiſtants he had in his time, whoſe Book was printed 1613. and again with Additions, 1625. and 1638. Biſhop <hi>Bramhall,</hi> and all the Aſſiſtance he could procure in his time, about the Year 1657. Dr. <hi>Burnet,</hi> incouraged by the Parliament 1679. and all the Helps and many Aſſiſtants he had; and the indefatigable Mr. <hi>Wharton,</hi> who had corrected and diſcovered ſo many Faults, Overſights and Miſtakes in others before him; beſides many others; that ever he was conſecrated at all. It is true Biſhop <hi>Godwin,</hi> Biſhop of <hi>Here<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ford,</hi> ſays, that he was conſecrated <hi>Feb.</hi> 22. 1535. but ſays neither where, nor by whom, nor produceth, or ſo much as refers to any
<pb n="5" facs="tcp:38423:4"/>Evidence or Proof of what he ſaith. And tho' Biſhop <hi>Bramhall</hi> would infer from thence that it was in <hi>Wales,</hi> and the Biſhop of <hi>Hereford</hi> might know ſomething of it; yet both Mr. <hi>Maſon</hi> and Mr. <hi>Wharton</hi> agree, and prove that what he ſaith cannot<note n="*" place="margin">He hath been found faulty in more things than this: But this he would u<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>doubtedly have cleared if he could.</note> be true. <hi>Maſon</hi> and <hi>Bramhall</hi> take much pains to prove it by <hi>Circumſtances</hi> and <hi>Probabilities,</hi> for that all things were done for him, and to him, and by him, that belong to a true and compleat Biſhop, except only that of Conſecration; and from the Concatenation of our <hi>Engliſh</hi> Cuſtoms; eſpecially from the <hi>Reſtitution of his Temporalities,</hi> which they would have us believe is always after Conſecration. But what<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ever it ought to be, either by Law or Cuſtom, it was not then always ſo obſerved, as before that, in the Caſe of <hi>Stokeſly,</hi> Biſhop of <hi>London,</hi> who had his Temporalities <hi>July</hi> 14. 1530. and was not conſecrated till <hi>Nov.</hi> 27. after, <hi>Whart. de Epiſc. Lond. p.</hi> 189. and ſince twice in the caſe of <hi>Bonner,</hi> who, elected Biſhop of <hi>Hereford,</hi> had Reſtitution of his Temporalities to his Proctor, while he him<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſelf was yet beyond Sea; and afterwards, elected Biſhop of <hi>London,</hi> had his Temporalities <hi>Nov.</hi> 18. 1539. and yet was not conſecrated till <hi>April</hi> 4. 1540. Nor is it more ſtrange, that of all the <hi>Acts</hi> neceſſary for that purpoſe, the Conſecration ſhould be omitted, and eſpecially at a time when it was ſet ſo light by, than that of all the <hi>Records</hi> and <hi>Entries</hi> of thoſe Acts, that<note n="*" place="margin">There muſt have been al<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſo a Commiſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſion for it, i<gap reason="illegible" resp="#UOM" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap> he had been conſecrated by others without the Arch-Biſhop</note> only of the Conſecration, if there had been any, ſhould be wanting, when all the other Acts appear in their proper Courts, as <hi>Bramhall</hi> tells us, <hi>p.</hi> 482. but after all, at laſt concludes: <hi>Neither doth this Conſecration concern us ſo much, as the Fathers</hi> (thoſe againſt whom he writes) <hi>imagine: there were Three Conſecrators (which is the Canonical Number) beſides him,</hi> ibid. and ſo <hi>Maſon, p.</hi> 370. and ſo both give up this point, and betake themſelves to another Refuge, of a Canonical Number without him, which will not hold neither, as I ſhall obſerve by and by. But, <hi>firſt,</hi> one word more of this principal Conſecrator, <hi>Barlow,</hi> who, I believe, was never conſecrated himſelf.</p>
            <p>He was electected <hi>Jan.</hi> 16. 1539/6. Biſhop of St. <hi>Aſaph,</hi> and con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>firmed the 23d and about the ſame time was in the King's Service in <hi>Scotland; Legationem apud Scotiae Regem, ab Henrico Angliae Regis miſſus, obiit,</hi> ſays <hi>Wharton:</hi> and <hi>April</hi> 10. following was elected Biſhop of St. <hi>David</hi>'s, the Tranſlation confirmed by the Arch-Biſhop the 21ſt. and the Temporalities reſtored the 26th of the ſame Month: but the Record mentions nothing of any Conſecra<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tion preceeding, but his Election and Confirmation by the Arch-Biſhop only: <hi>ipſumque ſic electum Epiſcopum praedictae Eccleſiae Me<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nevenſ. praefecit.</hi> The ſhort ſpace between his Election to St. <hi>Aſaph,</hi>
               <pb n="6" facs="tcp:38423:5"/>and Tranſlation to St. <hi>David</hi>'s, and his Abſence in <hi>Scotland,</hi> might well prevent his Conſecration for that time, and the <hi>Tranſlation,</hi> eſpecially if he continued any conſiderable time in <hi>Scotland,</hi> make his Conſecration when he came home never queſtioned or thought on, eſpecially having his Spiritualities by the Arch-Biſhop's Con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>firmation, and his Temporalities reſtored by the King. And it is like enough he might concur with the Arch-Biſhop in ſlight thoughts of ſuch a <hi>Formality.</hi> For what-ever was his <hi>Learning,</hi> it ſeems, his <hi>Virtue</hi> was ſo little, and the <hi>Offence,</hi> that he and <hi>Scory</hi> had given by their Behaviour, ſo great, that they were never ſo much as reſtored by Qu. <hi>Elizabeth</hi> to their former Sees, but put into meaner ones; as the Hiſtorian informs us in his <hi>Abridgment, p.</hi> 250. Nor would ſhe be Crowned by either of them, tho' ſhe could hardly get any other to do it: Nor ſhould <hi>Parker</hi> have been conſecrated by them if the other four in the firſt Commiſſion would have done it. But before his Election to St. <hi>Aſaph</hi> he had been an active Promoter of the Reformation in <hi>Wales,</hi> and ſo doubtleſs promoted his own In<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tereſt in the Favour of the King and <hi>Cranmer.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>Of the three Aſſiſtants, <hi>Scory</hi> and <hi>Coverdale</hi> were not Ca<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nonically elected, but promoted by Commiſſion, and conſecrated by <hi>Cranmer, Hodskins,</hi> and <hi>Ridley,</hi> by a new Form compoſed by Perſons appointed by the King, and authorized under the Great Seal, according to the Act of Parliament, and ſo ordered, that no Church of the <hi>Roman</hi> Communion, tho' they all look upon it as no leſs than Sacrilege to re-ordain any, who have been duly ordained before, have ever ſince allowed the Ordination of any ordained by them or their Succeſſors, or permitted them to perform the Office of Prieſts, without Re-ordination by ſome Biſhop of their own Communion.</p>
            <p>The laſt of the Three, who did actually aſſiſt, was <hi>Iohn <hi>Hodskins,</hi>
               </hi> only Suffragan of <hi>Bedford,</hi> conſecrated indeed <hi>An<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>no</hi> 29. <hi>Hen.</hi> 8. but when Commiſſions were in uſe, and therefore in the ſame caſe with thoſe of that time before-mentioned; and beſides, not rightly named in this Commiſſion, but by the Name of <hi>Richard,</hi> (<hi>v. Maſon, p.</hi> 414. <hi>Bramhall, p.</hi> 1025.) So that had he been without all other queſtion, yet his Legal Authority by this Commiſſion to act in this Conſecration is queſtionable.</p>
            <p>And here, before we proceed farther, it may be obſerved what <hi>a lame Cauſe</hi> this of the Conſecration of <hi>Matt. Parker</hi> is in all re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſpects, performed indeed by four Perſons, but of thoſe the firſt, and he to whom <hi>Parker</hi> is preſented to be conſecrated, never con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſecrated himſelf, that can be proved, and moſt likely never was.
<pb n="7" facs="tcp:38423:5"/>Again, when theſe great Champions, <hi>Maſon</hi> and <hi>Bramhall,</hi> after all their ſtruggle, cannot make that point out; they fly to another Refuge, and tell us, that there were three Conſecrators beſides him, and that that is the Canonical Number. But here we find another not rightly named in the Original Record: ſo that here is another Doubt; and if this hold, they fail of their Canonical Number even according to their own account: But be that as it may; if Three be the Canonical Number for others, it is certain it is not the Legal Number for an Arch-Biſhop, and when an Arch-Biſhop is not one, as is plain in the <hi>Stat.</hi> 25 <hi>Hen.</hi> 8. <hi>c.</hi> 20. So that they do deceitfully in that; and <hi>Parker</hi> therefore could be no Legal Arch-Biſhop: Nor was his Conſecration and Conſtitution Cano<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nical, or according to the Orders or Uſage of the Church of <hi>Eng<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>land</hi> in particular for near a Thouſand Years before, even from the beginning of the <hi>Engliſh</hi> Church, and of the whole Catholick Church, being confeſſedly the firſt of Seventy Arch-Biſhops con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſecrated in that manner, and without Patriarchal Approbation, a matter of no little Importance in the Kingdom of Chriſt, as may be ſhewed upon another Occaſion.</p>
            <p>In the <hi>Regiſter</hi> of this Conſecration publiſhed by <hi>Bramhall,</hi> I un<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>derſtand not how his Death, <hi>&amp;c.</hi> could be noted in that manner as it is printed, if it was not all written ſome time after that. Nor am I ſatisfied that it was ever printed in his Life-time, or ſo much as mentioned in any Book then in Print: but the Book pre<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tended for it, ſaid to be printed 1572. is ſo great a Rariety, that a Bookſeller told me he would give <hi>Five Pounds</hi> for it; and what is by <hi>Maſon</hi> alleadged out of it, <hi>lib.</hi> 3. <hi>c.</hi> 18. <hi>n.</hi> 12. proves it not; nor ſaith more than that he was elected, and conſecrated at ſuch a time, and by ſuch Perſons, but not one word of any Regiſter: and what he alleadgeth out of the Statute 8 <hi>Eliz. c.</hi> 1. is falſe, and groſsly fallacious; for the Statute hath not a word of any Regiſter, but of Records only, as Statutes and Records of Law, which he writing in <hi>Latin</hi> renders <hi>Archiva,</hi> to deceive and abuſe the Reader. So that there is no proof of this Regiſter in being at that time, or in 20 years after thoſe Records, which are entred in it. That ſuch a thing ſhould be done, and in ſuch extraordinary manner, as of Seventy Arch-Biſhops in that See, none before him was ſo ordered, as is related in his Life, and yet no Hiſtory of that time, or Letter, or other Writing, be found, which makes mention of the manner of it, or any Perſon but only one Lord, is ſo ſtrange, that it is in<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>credible it ſhould be done in any very publick manner, as is pre<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tended, what-ever was done. And that part intituled <hi>Rituum
<pb n="8" facs="tcp:38423:6"/>atque Ceremoniarum Ordo,</hi> is ſo preciſe and punctual in things of little moment, as if it was fitted up ſome time after to anſwer the Doubts and Queſtions which were made. And to ſend for Prieſts out of Priſons to ſee and teſtifie this Regiſter ſo long after, doth not ſo much confirm the Credibility, as the Suſpicion of the An<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tiquity and Authority of it. <hi>v. Maſon, lib.</hi> 3. <hi>c.</hi> 18. <hi>n.</hi> 11. And for farther Evidence, (if more need after ſo deceitful a Citation of a printed Statute) how little Truſt or Credit is to be given to the Authors of Mr. <hi>Maſon</hi>'s Book, the Citation of Mr. <hi>Wadſworth</hi>'s Letter Manuſcript, without noting the Date, the Pretence of others, who mention the Regiſter in Print, without the Names of the Authors, or Titles of the Books, and the alleadging <hi>Camden,</hi> Dr. <hi>Collins,</hi> and Dr. <hi>Hall,</hi> without the time when their Books were printed, which is all craftily done to impoſe upon the Reader, both do that effectually, and moreover ſhew how lame a cauſe it is in that particular alſo: For <hi>Wadſworth</hi>'s <hi>Letter,</hi> which is now in Print, is dated but <hi>April</hi> 1. 1615. and the other Books will be found print<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ed, I believe, but about the ſame time, which is nothing to the purpoſe. And what myſterious dealings there were about that time, the <hi>Convocation-Book,</hi> not long ſince publiſhed, which had been ſo long kept ſecret, is a notable Inſtance.</p>
            <p>But in what is without queſtion in that Regiſter, becauſe of Re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cord elſewhere, the Queens Letters Patent for his Confirmation and Conſecration, to which we may add, the Opinion of the Six Doctors, the moſt eminent of that Faculty <hi>England</hi> then afforded, ſaith <hi>Fuller,</hi> ſubjoined, there is what may ſatisfie that there was then ſuch <hi>Doubts and Queſtions</hi> concerning the matter of the Conſecration by thoſe Perſons, as made a <hi>ſpecial Clauſe for ſupply of all Defects</hi> by the Queens Supream Authority, thought requiſite to be inſerted. And yet, it ſeems, that would not ſerve the turn, but afterward, in the 8th year of her Reign, <hi>a ſpecial Act of Parliament,</hi> drawn with all the Skill that could have been uſed, had it been for an Anſwer in Chancery, was thought farther requiſite to ſettle the Authority of the new Biſhops. And tho' it be pretended, that they were only <hi>Queſtions at Law,</hi> which may be true, but with a <hi>Fallacy</hi> in it: for they aroſe upon matters firſt determinable by the Canons and Orders of the Church, as appears by the Judges Opinions reported by <hi>Brook</hi> concerning Leafes and Eſtates made by K. <hi>Edward</hi>'s Biſhops, that they were <hi>not good,</hi> becauſe they were <hi>not conſecrated,</hi> and therefore <hi>not Biſhops;</hi> yet if we look into <hi>the Original of thoſe Queſtions,</hi> we ſhall find they were not then Queſtions at Law, but poſitive Deter<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>minations by the Church, of the <hi>Nullity</hi> of their Conſecration, and
<pb n="9" facs="tcp:38423:6"/>
               <hi>Defect</hi> of Title. So <hi>Taylor</hi> of <hi>Lincoln</hi> was deprived <hi>ob Nullitatem Conſecrationis &amp; Defectum Tituli quem habuit à Rege Ed. per Lit. Pa<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tentes,</hi> and others the like. <hi>Ridley</hi> was degraded only of Prieſthood, becauſe they did not take him to be a Biſhop; but <hi>Cranmer</hi> of his Epiſcopal Dignity, becauſe he had been duly conſecrated. And no Church of the <hi>Roman</hi> Communion have ever ſince allowed the Or<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dination of this Church of <hi>England,</hi> eſtabliſhed by Law, to be good, or permitted any Perſon ordained in it to the Office of Prieſthood without Ordination by ſome other Biſhop either of the <hi>Latin,</hi> or of the <hi>Greek</hi> Church, tho' they hold it no leſs than Sacrilege to re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ordain one, who had been duly ordained before, as was before noted.</p>
            <p>Here was the Original of the Queſtions then made; but there is <hi>another Original</hi> precedent to this, which perhaps was not then taken notice of, or not conſidered as it deſerveth, <hi>of other Queſtions</hi> as conſiderable as any, which I have mentioned already; the <hi>Com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>miſſions</hi> introduced, undoubtedly by <hi>Cranmer, Anno</hi> 1535. For they contain matter not only contrary to the moſt ancient Canons, in thoſe words, <hi>Nos tuis in hac parte Supplicationibus inclinati:</hi> for thoſe Canons order ſuch as apply to Secular Powers in ſuch caſes, to be depoſed and excommunicated: but moreover, monſtrouſly Heretical in the <hi>Declaration,</hi> and Schiſmatical in the <hi>Delegation</hi> before-mentioned. Objections both of <hi>Hereſie</hi> and <hi>Schiſm</hi> have been made by others; but not for thoſe matters: and two things have been replied, which may be likewiſe in this caſe: The one, that <hi>Bonner,</hi> and all the reſt, and all Qu. <hi>Mary</hi>'s Biſhops, were in the ſame caſe; and therefore <hi>è verorum Epiſcoporum Albo in aeternum ex<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pungendi,</hi> ſaith <hi>Maſon, p.</hi> 185. is true in part, of thoſe who were in before her time: For <hi>Cranmer</hi> was not only the Projector and Promoter of that, and other ſuch wicked Inventions, but alſo the Decoy to betray the reſt into the Miſchiefs, as well as the Inſtru<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ment to betray the King and Kingdom into the Sin; and accor<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dingly was charged with both by <hi>Brooks,</hi> Biſhop of <hi>Glouceſter,</hi> in that Queen's time, as we are informed by the Hiſtorian, who would help him out; but 'tis with an Anſwer impoſſible to be true: yet as to the reſt it is falſe, and the Inference falſe: For all thoſe things were rectified in the Biſhops of her time: which cannot be ſaid of any of the reſt, either before or ſince. And the other, when well conſidered, will prove as falſe and deceitful; and ſo both ra<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ther confirm, than anſwer the Objection: It is grounded upon an Opinion of the Schoolmen, and the Councils of <hi>Florence</hi> and <hi>Trent;</hi> that neither <hi>Schiſm,</hi> nor <hi>Hereſie,</hi> can vacate the indelible Character of Epiſcopal Authority once duly and effectually conferred; no more
<pb n="10" facs="tcp:38423:7"/>than Baptiſm duly adminiſtred. But tho' generally the Baptiſm of Schiſmaticks and Hereticks hath been allowed for good upon their return to the Unity and Doctrine of the Church, yet were there ſpe<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cial caſes anciently, which were never allowed. And ſo, and much more in Orders, tho' generally this may hold, yet there may be ſuch Special caſes, wherein it may not hold: And ſuch I take this to be. For, if either the declared Opinion, or the matter of Fact, or both together, be inconſiſtent with the very End and Intention of Bap<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tiſm or Ordination, in ſuch ſpecial caſe they can neither be allowed to be good or valid. As if a <hi>Jew,</hi> or a <hi>Platoniſt,</hi> who denieth <hi>Jeſus Christ</hi> to be the Meſſiah, baptize another of the ſame Belief in the Name of the Father, Son, and Holy Ghoſt, this cannot be allowed to be Chriſtian Baptiſm. So if a Biſhop believe and profeſs that there is no other <hi>Chriſtian Sacrifice</hi> than vocal or mental Prayers and Alms, and ordain another, who believes and profeſſes the ſame, in manner and form otherwiſe ſufficient for Prieſts Orders, this cannot be thought a good Ordination to Prieſthood, or to confer more than Deacons Orders, if ſo much. And this is the common caſe of <hi>Proteſtants,</hi> and hath been ſo ever ſince <hi>Luther</hi>'s <hi>diſpute with the Devil,</hi> related by himſelf, tho' there are ſome of the moſt learned of another mind. And ſuch is plainly the caſe of the <hi>Com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>miſſions</hi> before-mentioned, which contain an expreſs <hi>Recognition</hi> of all Authority in the King, and by conſequence a <hi>Renunciation</hi> of all other, not only Papal, but Epiſcopal, more than what is derived from the Regal; and a <hi>Delegation</hi> only of ſuch: And therefore the Conſecrations, how-ever performed, of Perſons on both ſides acting under ſuch Commiſſions, could be no other than Solemnities, tho' Religious of Inveſtiture into ſuch Authority as is delegated by the Commiſſion: and that could be but Political, unleſs the King had had any truly Epiſcopal regularly derived from the Original Spe<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cial Commiſſion of Chriſt. Nor could ſuch Perſons convey any other to their Succeſſors.</p>
            <p>In this there was certainly <hi>Digitus Dei,</hi> the Wiſdom of a Divine Providence, to raiſe up an Adverſary to correct the Obſtinacy of the Church, which would not reform, and to raiſe an Emulation, and give Admonition of divers things amiſs: but ſo as to be but for a time, and therefore imperfect, as hath been rightly obſerved by a late Author. And the time ſeems now near expired. And therefore hath the ſame moſt Wiſe Providence now lately raiſed up a <hi>New Queſtion</hi> between the preſent <hi>Political Biſhops</hi> of this <hi>Legal Church,</hi> and ſuch an Advocate for thoſe of them who are deprived, as had unanſwerably aſſerted their Cauſe upon the true
<pb n="11" facs="tcp:38423:7"/>of the Kingdom of Chriſt, had they themſelves come in by thoſe: but effectually done more than ever he intended, by ſuch Evidence and Arguments, as by a plain and eaſie application to the Depri<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vations by <hi>Stat.</hi> 1 <hi>Eliz. c.</hi> 1. much more ſtrongly prove Queen <hi>Elizabeth</hi>'s Biſhops to have been meer Intruders, and therefore <hi>Nulli;</hi> and that the Contenders on both ſides are no better them<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſelves than they whoſe Succeſſors they are; and the Cauſe he is in<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>gaged in beſides indefenſible, without diſclaiming the Principles of the Reformation, and of the preſent Conſtitution of this Church. This may be ſeen in the <hi>Vindication of the Deprived Biſhops, aſſerting their Spiritual Rights against a Lay-Deprivation,</hi> printed <hi>Anno</hi> 1692. 40. if it can be had, or in the <hi>Abſtract</hi> of it lately printed and the <hi>Application</hi> in the <hi>Letter to the Vindicator.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>What-ever may be allowed in matters of the World, I think it a very profane and wicked thing, in Arguments of Religion to uſe any thing of Deceit, Fallacy, or Cavilling; for they ought not to be mentioned but with Reverence: But when the Hand of God appears ſo manifeſt in bringing ſuppreſſed Truth to Light, it is dangerous to neglect it, much more to oppoſe it in ſuch manner, leſt they who do it ſhould be found to fight even againſt God. And therefore I hope this will be very ſeriouſly and well conſi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dered, by all ſincere and truly conſcientious People: and not only the Caſe that this Nation is in, but alſo the Duty of ſuch Circum<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtances both at home, and in reſpect of the Church of God abroad.</p>
            <p>And, <hi>firſt,</hi> it is to be conſidered, Whether God hath not con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cluded, as I may ſay, all under Sin? And whether that doth not oblige all to Humiliation under His mighty Hand, and mutual Condeſcention and Charity to one another? Whether this, which by vain Men hath been cryed up for a <hi>Glorious Church,</hi> doth not appear at laſt to be <hi>no Church at all?</hi> and their Clergy, who were thought the Glory of it, be not a meer <hi>Political Order,</hi> un<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>happily introduced and ſubſtituted in the Place of ſuch, as derive their Authority from the Commiſſion of Chriſt to his Apoſtles, but, in truth, are no more than<note n="*" place="margin">The two principal parts of Prieſthood are partly r<gap reason="illegible" resp="#UOM" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap>
                  <g ref="char:EOLunhyphen"/>jected, ar<gap reason="illegible" resp="#UOM" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap> partly ne<gap reason="illegible" resp="#UOM" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap>
                  <g ref="char:EOLunhyphen"/>lected: ar<gap reason="illegible" resp="#UOM" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap> juſtly for want of A<gap reason="illegible" resp="#UOM" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap>
                  <g ref="char:EOLunhyphen"/>thority, wh<gap reason="illegible" resp="#UOM" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap>
                  <g ref="char:EOLunhyphen"/>ther by Pr<gap reason="illegible" resp="#UOM" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap>
                  <g ref="char:EOLunhyphen"/>vidence, <gap reason="illegible" resp="#UOM" extent="1 word">
                     <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
                  </gap> Conſcience or both.</note> meerly <hi>Teachers,</hi> as the diſſent<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing Miniſters are commonly and properly ſo called by their Peo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ple? For without a duly authorized Miniſtry, all agree, there can be no Church, properly ſo called. Nay, Whether the diſſenting Miniſters of all Parties have not the Advantage both in the Inno<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cency, and in the Authority of their Calling? in the Innocency, becauſe they do not betray the Rights of the Church of Chriſt: and in the Authority, becauſe from Chriſtian Aſſemblies, and not from the Civil Power, which may be <hi>Jews, Mahometans, Infidels</hi> or
<pb n="12" facs="tcp:38423:8"/>
               <hi>Atheiſts.</hi> And whether the Fruits and Effects of their Miniſtry be not as good and plentiful in their Congregations, as the other in their Pariſhes, and Dioceſſes? Where are better Fruits than Mr. <hi>Baxter</hi>'s at <hi>Kiderminſter?</hi> or Mr. <hi>Elliot</hi>'s in <hi>America?</hi>
            </p>
            <p>And as to <hi>the Church of God abroad,</hi> doth not Mr. <hi>Baxter,</hi> on the one ſide, and Biſhop <hi>Bramhall,</hi> on the other, reckon up whole Heads of falſe and groundleſs Charges which have been raiſed againſt them? Hath not God by his Providence removed the Motives of temporal Intereſt, which partly promoted, and partly ſupported the pretended Reformation under that firſt Race of Princes; and ſo altered the caſe, that the preſent Conſtitution is not defenſible without diſclaiming thoſe falſe Principles? Hath He not prepared the way to a Reconciliation and Peace in the Church, and a more effectual Peace in Chriſtian States, by the Peace lately concluded by the Means of a Confederacy with Ca<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tholick Princes? And would not a Propoſal of Juſt and Reaſon<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>able Terms of Accommodation and true Chriſtian Union, oblige the other ſide to a Reformation of much of what is amiſs, and much mend our own Caſe? Hath not this Holy Providence diſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>covered to us a Neceſſity we are under to do it? And would not this be a Glorious Work for King <hi>William</hi> to undertake, and the Crown and Glory of all to accompliſh it, and demonſtrate Him an Inſtrument raiſed up by God indeed? And can he be a Loyal Subject in the Kingdom of Chriſt, who would not do his utmoſt endeavour to promote a matter of ſo much importance to it? Certainly he can be no Loyal Subject of the Kingdom of <hi>England,</hi> who can ſee things in ſuch a Caſe, and be afraid to ſpeak it. If all this be not <hi>a Providential Call,</hi> I know not what is; but think it no Wiſdom for any Man to experiment the Truth of it, by a dangerous Neglect. What the over-ruling Providence of God ſeems now to call, to lead, and even conſtrain us to, by removing Obſtacles, affording Opportunities, and diſcovering ſo great a Ne<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ceſſity and Obligation, is no more than what hath been long ſince thought neceſſary, and much deſired by divers very Learned, Ju<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dicious, Moderate and Pious Perſons: And I believe it will prove the trueſt Wiſdom to conſider theſe Works of God, and conform to the Motions of the Supream Wiſdom, leaſt we kick againſt the Prick, and daſh upon a Rock.</p>
            <trailer>FINIS.</trailer>
            <pb facs="tcp:38423:8"/>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
